<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on A minimal Hugo website</title>
    <link>https://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on A minimal Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Post #7: State Level Predictions</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/10/21/super-ensembling-simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/10/21/super-ensembling-simulations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;national-two-party-vote-share&#34;&gt;National Two Party Vote Share&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;table style=&#34;border-collapse:collapse; border:none;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;caption style=&#34;font-weight: bold; text-align:left;&#34;&gt;2024 Democrat Two Party Vote Share via Linear Regression&lt;/caption&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;th style=&#34;border-top: double; text-align:center; font-style:italic; font-weight:normal; padding:0.2cm; border-bottom:1px solid black; text-align:left; &#34;&gt;Prediction&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;th style=&#34;border-top: double; text-align:center; font-style:italic; font-weight:normal; padding:0.2cm; border-bottom:1px solid black; &#34;&gt;Lower.Bound&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;th style=&#34;border-top: double; text-align:center; font-style:italic; font-weight:normal; padding:0.2cm; border-bottom:1px solid black; &#34;&gt;Upper.Bound&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;td style=&#34; padding:0.2cm; text-align:left; vertical-align:top; text-align:left; border-bottom: double; &#34;&gt;53.31%&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;td style=&#34; padding:0.2cm; text-align:left; vertical-align:top; text-align:center; border-bottom: double; &#34;&gt;46.57%&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;td style=&#34; padding:0.2cm; text-align:left; vertical-align:top; text-align:center; border-bottom: double; &#34;&gt;60.05%&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;linear-model&#34;&gt;Linear Model&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## [1] &amp;quot;In-sample MSE for Optimized LM Model: 1.77876259651781&amp;quot;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pr</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week #6: Improving Electoral College Model</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/10/14/week-6-improving-model-spending/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/10/14/week-6-improving-model-spending/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post #5: State Level Predictions</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/10/07/post-5-state-level-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/10/07/post-5-state-level-predictions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This week’s post builds on last week’s and introduces the structure followed in each post leading up to the election. I will develop two models to predict the national two-party popular vote and forecast the Electoral College outcome. These models will be updated with new data, such as recent polls, and enhanced with additional variables and prediction methods to fine-tune our projections.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;national-two-party-vote-predictions&#34;&gt;National Two-Party Vote Predictions&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I decided to shift away from using a weighted polling average and instead focus on a simple average of polls from weeks 5 to 8. The main reason for this change is that the weighted polling average, constructed by regressing historical data on each week, resulted in an artificially high R-squared of around 0.95 when recent poll data was added. This high correlation occurred because the weighted polling average was based on the same outcome factor being regressed again, leading to a model that seemed highly accurate but was likely over fitting to past data.  By switching to an average of polls from weeks 5 to 8, I aim to use a more straightforward metric, which should offer better predictive power without inflating the model’s performance. I will later explain why I chose this specific period.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post #4: Will Incumbency Matter?</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/09/30/post-4-will-incumbency-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/09/30/post-4-will-incumbency-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Typically, the question of incumbency in an election is straightforward: either one of the candidates is the sitting president, or they aren’t. Of course, in 2024, no question is that simple.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this week’s post, I’ll address a few key questions: how to factor Kamala Harris’ status as an incumbent in predictions, whether incumbency has a significant effect on forecasts, and how my models compare to Abramowitz’s Time for Change model, which emphasizes incumbency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post #3: Polling</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/09/23/post-3-polling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/09/23/post-3-polling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For many, polling is considered the foundation of electoral predictions. However, its predictive power may be significantly less reliable than expected. In this week’s post, I explore this by creating a few predictive models for national and state races using only polling data, and I analyze the results.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite polling’s prominence, the circumstances surrounding this election make data particularly limited. Since President Biden exited the race in mid-July, there are only eight weeks of polling data available that directly compares the current two candidates. This data spans from 15 weeks before the election to 7 weeks prior, which presents some challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post #2: Modeling Using the Economy</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/09/16/post-2-modeling-using-the-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/09/16/post-2-modeling-using-the-economy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The economy is often cited as a core &amp;lsquo;fundamental&amp;rsquo; in predicting election outcomes. A strong economy typically suggests that the incumbent party is likely to win and vice versa. In some elections, like in 1980, where rampant inflation—significantly rising gas prices—dominated, it was clear that incumbent Jimmy Carter would lose due to the weak economy. However, in other elections, such as 2012 or 2016, it was less clear whether the economy was strong enough to predict an incumbent party victory.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post #1: Defining the Swing States</title>
      <link>https://example.org/post/2024/09/09/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.org/post/2024/09/09/post-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the first of a series of blog posts in which I will analyze and predict the 2024 Presidential Election. In my first post, I will analyze historical data from past presidential elections to determine how competitive presidential elections are, what states can be seen as reliable for either party, while what states are considered swing states.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-states-are-competitive&#34;&gt;What states are competitive?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To begin, I will examine the vote margins for each state in the Democratic and Republican parties&amp;rsquo; presidential elections from 2000 to 2020. A brief overview shows that even the most partisan states had relatively close margins. Excluding D.C., every state was within 30 percentage points, and most were within 15 points. However, under the U.S. Electoral College system, whether state margins are 80-20 or 52-48, if they consistently vote for the same party, the margin does not affect the overall election outcome. The only states that genuinely impact the result are those with razor-thin margins capable of switching sides, and these states tend to be nearly white on the electoral map below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
